{"test_questions": [[{"question": "On the ribosome, mRNA binds", "opta": "between the subunits", "optb": "to the large subunit", "optc": "to the small subunit", "optd": "none of these", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Type I proteins (plasma membrane) have a", "opta": "cleavage N- terminal signal sequence and a hydrophobic stop transfer sequence", "optb": "cleavaged N- terminal signal sequence that doubles as the membrane anchoring sequence", "optc": "multiple signal sequence and a hydrophobic stop transfer sequence", "optd": "multiple signal sequence that doubles as the membrane anchoring sequence", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following is not a necessary component of translation?", "opta": "Anticodon", "optb": "mRNA", "optc": "Ligase", "optd": "Amino acid", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A polysome could be best described as", "opta": "an active site of DNA synthesis.", "optb": "an active site of protein synthesis.", "optc": "an active site of lipid synthesis.", "optd": "all of the above.", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Eukaryotic mRNA binding to the ribosomes is facilitated by __________ .", "opta": "the Shine Dalgarno sequence", "optb": "the 7-methyl guanosine cap", "optc": "tRNA", "optd": "poly A tail", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Amino acids are joined together into a protein chain by which of the following?", "opta": "Transfer RNA", "optb": "DNA polymerase", "optc": "Hydrogen bonds", "optd": "Messenger RNA", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Phosphorus is taken up by the cell during the process of", "opta": "carbohydrate synthesis.", "optb": "protein synthesis,", "optc": "lipid synthesis.", "optd": "ATP synthesis.", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Protein synthesis rates in prokaryotes are limited by the rate of mRNA synthesis. If RNA synthesis occurs at the rate of 50 nucleotides/sec, then rate of protein synthesis occurs at", "opta": "10 amino acids/sec", "optb": "17 amino acids/sec", "optc": "25 amino acids/sec", "optd": "50 amino acids/sec", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The site of protein synthesis is", "opta": "Ribosome", "optb": "Nucleus", "optc": "Endoplasmic reticulum", "optd": "Chromosome", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The structure in a bacterium that indicates an active site for protein synthesis is", "opta": "a chromosome.", "optb": "a cell membrane,", "optc": "a flagellum.", "optd": "a polysome.", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The lac operon contains the z, y and a structural genes", "opta": "encoding p-galactosidase, galactose permeases and thio-galactosidase transacetylase respectively", "optb": "encoding p-galactosidase and galactose permeases", "optc": "encoding P-galactosidase only", "optd": "None of the above", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Proteins contain __________ different amino acids, whereas DNA and RNA are composed of __________ different nucleotides", "opta": "20,64", "optb": "3,20", "optc": "4,20", "optd": "20,4", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following is not necessary for protein synthesis to occur, once transcription is completed?", "opta": "tRNA", "optb": "Ribosomes", "optc": "mRNA", "optd": "DNA", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Ribosomes select the correct tRNAs", "opta": "then bind to the appropriate mRNA", "optb": "solely on the basis of their anticodons", "optc": "depending on their abundance in the cytosol", "optd": "with the least abundant anticodons", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Signal peptide protein removal that is translocated across a membrane is accomplished by", "opta": "fMet aminopeptidase", "optb": "trypsin", "optc": "signal peptidase", "optd": "chymotrypsin", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The direction of amino acid transfer to the growing polypeptide chain is", "opta": "from the A (aminoacyl tRNA site) site to the P (peptidyl tRNA site) site on the ribosome", "optb": "from the P site to the A site on the ribosome", "optc": "from the A site to the E (exit tRNA site) site on the ribosome", "optd": "from the P site to the E site on the ribosome", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The pathway of a tRNA during polypeptide elongation on the ribosome is", "opta": "A site \u2192 P site \u2192 E site", "optb": "P site \u2192 entry site \u2192 exit site", "optc": "A site \u2192 P site \u2192 entry site", "optd": "P site \u2192 A site \u2192 E site", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following has unusual bases?", "opta": "mRNA", "optb": "tRNA", "optc": "rRNA", "optd": "hnRNA", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The site on a bacterial chromosome that marks the termination point for chromosome replication is called", "opta": "ter", "optb": "a stop codon.", "optc": "a stem-loop", "optd": "pau", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Degenerated codon differs mostly in", "opta": "the identities of their second base", "optb": "the identities of their third base", "optc": "the wobble position", "optd": "both (b) and (c)", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Translation in prokaryotes begins by the formation of a 30S initiation complex between the", "opta": "30S ribosomal subunit, mRNA, initiation factors and N-fMet tRNA", "optb": "30S ribosomal subunit, tRNA and initiation factors", "optc": "30S ribosomal subunit and mRNA only", "optd": "30S ribosomal subunit, mRNA and initiation factors", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The anticodon of tRNA", "opta": "binds to rRNA", "optb": "binds to an amino acid", "optc": "binds to the Shine Dalgarno sequence", "optd": "binds to an mRNA codon", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The peptidyl transferase reaction occurs", "opta": "on the large subunit", "optb": "on the small subunit", "optc": "between the subunit", "optd": "none of these", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Processive synthesis is a characteristic feature of", "opta": "all DNA polymerases.", "optb": "DNA Pol III at a replication fork.", "optc": "removal of RNA primers on Okasaki fragments.", "optd": "DNA mismatch repair", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which site of the tRNA molecule binds to the mRNA molecule?", "opta": "Anticodon", "optb": "Codon", "optc": "Amino acid", "optd": "5 prime end", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The first step in translation is", "opta": "binding of the two ribosomal subunits to each other", "optb": "binding of mRNA to the two ribosomal subunits", "optc": "binding of tRNA to the small ribosomal subunit", "optd": "binding of mRNA to the small ribosomal subunit", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following amino acid starts all proteins synthesis?", "opta": "Glycine", "optb": "Proline", "optc": "Thymine", "optd": "Methionine", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The growing polypeptide chain is released from the ribosomes when", "opta": "a chain terminating codon is reached", "optb": "a chain terminating tRNA binds to the ribosome", "optc": "the 7-methyl guanosine cap is reached", "optd": "the poly A tail is reached", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following RNAs bind to an amino acid?", "opta": "mRNA", "optb": "tRNA", "optc": "rRNA", "optd": "hnRNA", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "How many bases of nucleic acid determine a single amino acid?", "opta": "Four", "optb": "One", "optc": "Two", "optd": "Three", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The ribosomes are composed of", "opta": "proteins", "optb": "RNA", "optc": "both (a) and (b)", "optd": "lipids", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which is required for protein synthesis?", "opta": "tRNA", "optb": "mRNA", "optc": "rRNA", "optd": "All of these", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}]]}